One more!
(日向翔陽)
もう一本もう一本来い
Gimme one more!
Shut up! You don't need to tell me!
(影山飛雄)
うるせぇ分かてんだよ行くぞ
Here it comes!
Yeah!
Man, that felt amazing!
ひょ気持ちいい
((ボルの重さが
こう手にズシとくる感じ
And I can feel the full weight of the ball in my palm.
大好きです
I love it!
よしゃ
Hell yeah!
対ネコ戦も速攻決めるぞ
(東峰)え
Our fast attacks are gonna run roughshod over Neko!
駒と試合
Neko?
They're playing Nekoma?
(澤村)ゴルデンウｨク最終日に
練習試合なんだ
We're playing a practice match at the end of Golden Week.
げ
｢げ｣てなんだ
Ack!
What was that for? And stop running from me!
おい逃げるな
だてお前怒ると怖いんだもん
I don't want to be anywhere near you when you get mad.
今別に怒てないだろ
But I'm not mad right now!
駒のことて
Well, talk of Nekoma always sounded like a history lesson to us.
昔話みたいな感じで聞いてたし
駒に
何か因縁があるわけじゃない
Our teams don't really have that rivalry anymore.
でも
｢猫対烏ゴミ捨て場の決戦｣
That said,
the "Battle of the Garbage Dumpster: Cat vs Crow" is making a comeback!
よく話に聞いてたあのネコと今
We've heard so much about Neko, and now we're gonna be playing them for the first time in years.
俺たちが
数年ぶりに再戦てなると
ちょとテンション上がるよな
Doesn't that get you a little hyped?
けど俺はスガにも西谷にも
But I don't know how to face Suga or Nishinoya.
合わせる顔がない
またくお前は
Oh, come on.
でかい図体して
相変わらずへなちょこだな
For all your size, you're still a wimp on the inside, huh?
西谷と対極にも程がある
You and Nishinoya are like polar opposites.
(東峰)も少し
言葉をオブラトに包めよ
Can't you sugarcoat your words a little?
安心しろ
スガはもちろん西谷も問題ない
Relax.
Neither Suga nor Nishinoya will have a problem with it.
お前と違て懐が深いからなぁ
Unlike you, they have big hearts.
お前基本
優しいキャラじゃなかたけ
Weren't you supposed to be an all-round nice guy?
お前は対象外だ
へなちょこだから
You get special treatment,
wimp that you are.
う
(澤村)ひと月もサボたこととか
Who cares if you played hooky for a month?
なんかいろいろ気まずいとか
来づらいとか
So what if things are awkward and you're finding it hard to show up?
そういうの関係ないからな
None of that matters.
(澤村)まだ
バレが好きかもしれないなら
If there's a chance you might still like volleyball,
戻てくる理由は十分だ
then that's reason enough to come back.
(澤村)あそれとな
Oh, and one more thing.
エスに夢抱いてるヤツも
いるんだからな
You can't let a guy who idolizes aces down, right?
ガ
痛
Ow!
Foot of the Slope
On the bank of the flowing Hirose River...
(繋心)
Episode Nine:
A Set For the Ace
I'm remembering what can't return...
(繋心)
In the dancing brightness of the rapids...
うわな何してる
Wh-What are you doing?!
(武田)あすみません
お客さんがいないか確認を
I'm sorry! I was checking to see if you had customers.
Is this about coaching again?
またコチの話かよ
(武田)はい
Yes.
(繋心)俺は今でも
プレするのが好きなんだ
I still love to play.
町内にチムだて作てる
コチなんてやたら
I put together a neighborhood team.
I'd hate being a coach 'cause I'd be dying to join in.
ムズムズしそうで嫌だ
(武田)はあ
I see.
それに
あの体育館に行きたくない
Besides, I don't want to go near that gym.
な何か嫌な思い出でも
その逆だ
D-Do you have bad memories of the place?
The opposite! It's packed with memories of my youth.
あそこには青春が詰まている
じゃあなんで
Then why?
(繋心)あの体育館とか部室が
昔と変わらなくても
I don't care if that gym and our clubroom haven't changed.
俺があそこに戻ることは
絶対にできない
I absolutely can't go back there.
あの限られた時間の独特の感じ
The limited time I spent there felt unique.
あの場所のあの時間にしかない
空気みたいな
It's like breathing the air from a bygone era.
ノスタルジですかぁ
いいなぁ
So you're nostalgic? You're lucky.
うるせぇな
Oh, be quiet!
だから戻りたくない
That's why I don't want to go back there!
駒高校が来るとしても
え
What if I said Nekoma High was coming?
(武田)ゴルデンウィク最終日
うちと５年ぶりの練習試合です
At the end of Golden Week, we have our first practice match with them in five years.
なんで今
What did... you just say?
向こうは
烏養監督と親交の深かた
Coach Nekomata, who had such a profound friendship with Coach Ukai, has recently come out of retirement.
猫又監督が
最近復帰されたそうです
それを聞いて
練習試合をお願いしてみたんです
When I heard this, I asked for a practice match.
(繋心)え
烏養君たちの時代は
In your day, wasn't that when the two teams had the closest ties?
駒との交流が
深かた時期じゃないですか
(繋心)ああ
そういえば
Yeah.
Which reminds me, their current coach
played setter at Nekoma 7 or 8 years ago.
駒でセタだた方が
今コチをされてるそうですよ
(直井)
((今年が最後のチｬンスだ烏養
This year will be our final chance, Ukai.
必ず必ず全国で会うぞ))
I want to see you at nationals, got it?
(繋心)((おお必ずだ
Right!
I'll be there!
(武田)ちょうど
烏養君も現役の頃だから
That was when you were part of the volleyball team,
もしかしたら
顔見知りかもしれないですね
so perhaps you two know one another.
(繋心)おい
ん
Hey.
あおてんのかてめぇ
うわすいませんすいません
Are you trying to aggravate me?!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
(繋心)ふざけんなそんな
あからさまにあおられてなぁ
Bullshit! You're obviously trying to aggravate me! Do you seriously think that's gonna work?!
俺が乗かると思てんのか
練習何時からだおらぁ
When does practice start?!
I'm sorr—
すいまえ
Huh?
駒が来るつうのに
Um...
I can't allow Nekoma to see my juniors in their current deplorable state!
みともない後輩
見せてたまるか
I'm getting changed! Stay right there!
着替えてくる待とけ
ははい
Sure!
(繋心)母ちゃん店番頼む
Mom, mind the store for me!
よし
Yes!
(繋心)
ああもしもしたつぁん
Yeah, hello? Tattsuan?
(田中)なあノヤさん
(西谷)あ
Say, Noya?
Yeah?
(田中)こち来れない間の特訓て
何やてたんだ
How did you train while you were suspended?
ん
主にブロクフォロだな
I focused on blocked ball retrieval.
ブロクされたボルを
拾いまくる特訓
Specialized training to retrieve any blocked ball!
なかなか
うまくできねぇんだけど
I'm not that great at it,
but if I can just retrieve blocked balls,
ブロクフォロが
ちゃんとできれば
お前らももと安心して
スパイク打てるだろ
you guys can go for your spikes without worrying as much.
≪こいつ見る度違うとこに
青アザつくて
The guy seems to have a bruise in a new place every time I see him.
Noya, you are totally, utterly cool!
あんたマジかちょいいヤツ
何泣いてんだお前
Why are you crying?!
(武田)お疲れさま
Hello!
(澤村)集合
(２人)え
Gather 'round!
紹介します今日から
コチをお願いする烏養君です
Allow me to introduce you to Ukai, your coach as of today!
(澤村)
ココチ本当ですか
Coach?
Do you mean it?!
駒との試合までだからな
(澤村)はあ
Only for the duration of your match with Nekoma.
Oh.
(田中)えでも
坂ノ下商店のにいちゃんだよな
What? He's the guy who runs Foot of the Slope right?
ほんとにコチ
(武田)彼は君たちの先輩で
Is he really our coach?
He graduated from Karasuno,
and he's the grandson of the famous Coach Ukai.
あの烏養監督のお孫さんです
(一同)ええ
What?!
でもお店の名前
｢坂ノ下｣じゃないの
But your store isn't named after you, right? I mean, sir?!
あですか
(繋心)母方の実家の店なんだよ
The store comes from mom's side of the family.
時間ねぇんだささとやるぞ
There's no time! Let's get started!
お前らがどんな感じか見てぇから
６時半からゲムな
I want to see how you guys play, so we have a match at 6:30.
相手はもう呼んである
(澤村)え相手
I called in your opponents.
Opponents?
烏野町内会チムだ
The Karasuno Neighborhood Association team.
(澤村)((まだ
バレが好きかもしれないなら
If there's a chance you might still like volleyball,
戻てくる理由は十分だ))
then that's reason enough to come back.
カァカァ
うす
I'm going in!
Right!
行きます
I'm going!
くそ出やしねぇ
Damn, he isn't picking up.
やぱり平日のこの時間に
全員は無理か
I guess assembling the gang this late on a weekday was too much to ask.
Here.
(山口)
あありがとうございます
Th-Thank you.
(滝ノ上)ういす
(嶋田)うす
Hello!
Yo.
(内沢)うは
(森)懐かしい
Damn!
This takes me back!
Excuse me?
チム町内会
Team Neighborhood Association...
(４人)参上
...is on the scene!
(繋心)おう
悪いなお前ら急に来てもらて
Hey! Thanks for coming out at the drop of a hat like this, guys!
(月島)町内会て言うから
もとおさんかと思てたのに
That's for sure!
I envisioned older guys when he said neighborhood association.
You owe me one.
Oh, fine.
俺も
Same here.
(繋心)よしそろそろ始めるぞ
Okay, let's get this thing started!
(一同)おす
試合だ
Yeah!
Game on!
んなんだお前どうした
あ
Hey, you. What's wrong?
(澤村)あすみません
そいつはちょと
I'm sorry. He's not ready.
(繋心)
なんだ訳ありかケガか
What's the deal? Issues? Injury?
No, it's not that straightforward.
(澤村)いや
そういうわけじゃないんですが
(繋心)
なんだよケガじゃねぇの
What, so he's not injured?
I dunno what the deal is, but join the neighborhood team.
よく分かんねぇけど
町内会チム入てくれよ
こちのリベロ
仕事で来られないんだよ
Our libero is tied up at work.
(澤村)あそれなら
Oh, in that case.
(繋心)
あと２人かどうすかな
What'll we do about the other two?
そちまだ何人かいるよな
あ旭さんだ
You have more people, right?
Hey! It's Asahi!
(２人)え
旭さん
Asahi!
げまたこいつ
Ugh! Him again.
I was just, um...
あお俺はその
(田中)旭さん
Asahi?!
A tardy guy? Are you jerkin' my chain?!
(繋心)なんだ遅刻か
なめてんのかポジションどこだ
State your position!
(東峰)えウイングスパイカ
(繋心)人足んねぇんだ
Wing spiker.
We need players! Get the hell in here and get warmed up!
ささと入てアプ取れ
すぐすぐ
Make it snappy!
(２人)あぁ
(繋心)あとはセタか
Now all we need is a setter.
俺やりてぇけど
外から見てなきゃだしなぁ
I wanna do it, but I have to watch from the outside.
お前らの方から
セタ１人貸してくれ
Loan me one of your setters.
Sugawara!
菅原さん
俺に譲るとかじゃないですよね
You're not deferring to me, are you?
菅原さんが退いて
俺が繰り上げみたいの
If rising in the ranks comes at your expense, I'm out.
ごめんですよ
(菅原)俺は影山が入てきて
This whole time, I prepared to fight you for the starting position.
正セタ争いしてやるて
思う反面
どかで
ほとしてた気がする
But after you joined the team,
I think I felt relieved somehow.
セタは
チムの攻撃の軸だ
The setter is a team's attack axis.
いちばん
頑丈でなくちゃいけない
He must be steadfast.
でも俺は
トスを上げることにビビてた
But I was too freaked out to set properly.
俺のトスで
I was so afraid of submitting the spiker to repeated blocks because of my sets,
またスパイカが何度も
ブロクに捕まるのが怖くて
圧倒的な実力の
影山の陰に隠れて
that I hid in the shadow of
Kageyama's overwhelming talent.
安心してたんだ
It was comfortable there.
(菅原)スパイクが
ブロクに捕まる瞬間考えると
The very thought of a spike being blocked still scares me.
今も怖いけど
That said...
もう一回
俺にトス上げさせてくれ旭
Please let me set for you one more time, Asahi.
(菅原)だから
俺はこちに入るよ影山
That's why I'm going on this side.
And Kageyama?
負けないからな
I'm not gonna lose.
俺もす
Me neither.
西谷ナイスレシブ頼むよ
当然す
Nishinoya, give me those good receives of yours!
Naturally!
(澤村)よし早く準備しろよ
旭さん来たなな
Okay, let's get ready!
Asahi came! See?
ああとりあえずな
Yeah, for now.
Karasuno        Neighborhood Assoc.
(一同)お願いします
Let's have a good match!
He really is intimidating.
(澤村)さすがに威圧感あるなぁ
(滝ノ上)さあ来い高校生
Come at me, high schoolers!
≪エスと対決だ≫
It's a showdown against the ace!
Haikyuu !!
Karasuno          Neighborhood Assoc.
(嶋田)ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
(縁下)う
(滝ノ上)おお
いい感じいい感じナイストス
Looking good!
Nice set.
あありがとうございます
Thank you, sir!
Sugawara's fast attack!
菅原さんの速攻
Well, duh. Suga is a respectable setter in his own right!
そらお前スガだて
れきとしたセｯタなんだからな
(２人)≪うれしそうだ≫
He looks so happy.
スガさんナイストス
おう
Suga, nice set!
つても
町内会チムの人たちが
Only because they're adjusting their team play for my benefit.
うまく
合わせてくれてるんだけどな
They're real veterans.
さすがベテランて感じだ
(滝ノ上)よしゃ
My setting still needs work.
(菅原)
俺自身のトスはまだまだだよ
でも速攻もどんどん使て
We need to keep using fast attacks and play hardball, or the match will ride on the ace again like before.
強気で
攻撃組み立てていかないと
またエスに頼りきりの試合に
なちゃうからな
スガさん
かちょよくなたすね
Suga, you've gotten really cool.
What? You think so?
(菅原)えそう
西谷に言われると
That's kinda awesome, coming from you.
なんかうれしいな
(西谷)えなんでですか
Why is that?
(菅原)いやあははは
You know...
Suga, you've gotten really reliable since I last saw you.
≪スガちょと見ないうちに
頼もしくなた
西谷の頼もしさは
相変わらずだ
Nishinoya is as reliable as ever.
No, I mean it. You've gotten really cool.
なのに俺はフラフラ戻てきて
But here I am, drifting back to the team and standing on the court again.
成り行きだけで
またコトに立てる
情けないと思うけど
It's pathetic.
However...
(森)ナイサ
(内沢)もう一本
You can do it!
One more!
(東峰)≪けど
However, I really do love it here.
やぱりここが好きだ≫
うわなんだ
What the?
よしゃ
うし
Right on!
That guy really flew!
(内沢)すげぇ跳んだなおい
すげぇドンピシャなトス
That set was dead-on.
あぁ
ふふふ
(澤村)ナイス日向影山
Good job, Hinata, Kageyama!
But now, with this guy setting for me, I can evade any block, no matter how high it may be.
((今はこいつのトスがあるから
どんな高いブロｯクもかわせます))
((目の前のブロクが
いなくなて
The blockers vanish from my sight,
and I get a clear view of the other side of the net.
ネトの向こう側が
ばあと見えるんです))
(東峰)≪ネトの向こう側
The other side of the net.
((く
((ピ
(伊達工応援団)((わあ
Shake it off!
((ドンマイ
((もう一本
One more!
68th Annual Prefectural
Volleyball Tournament
Date Tech              Karasuno
(菅原)((フェイントだ前
It's a bluff! Forward!
((ナイスノヤさん
((旭
Nice, Noya!
Asahi!
((ピ
(伊達工応援団)((わあ
The Iron Wall of Date
((くそ
Shit.
(観客)((失敗したけど
すげぇよなあのリベロ))
They failed, but their libero is amazing.
I'm sorry! I'll save the next one!
((すみません次拾います
(観客)((うんすげぇレベル高い))
Yeah. He's on another level.
If it wasn't for that attacker...
(観客)((けど攻撃がなぁ
(東峰)≪またブロク
もう何本目かも分かんねぇ
Blocked again.
I've lost count of them now.
何度もトスを呼んだ
I called for so many sets.
俺に持てこい
俺が決めてやる
"Send them my way. I'll make them count."
But when all was said and done...
だけど最後の最後
トスを呼ぶのが怖くなた≫
I became too scared to call for the set.
((旭さん
((旭
Asahi?!
Asahi?
Suga, right!
(澤村)((スガライト
((大地
D-Daichi!
((く
Date Tech              Karasuno
(伊達工応援団)((わあ
(西谷)((くそ
((カン
Shit!
((ブロクのフォロ
全然できなかた
I couldn't retrieve a single blocked ball!
(東峰)
((なんでだなんで責めない
Why?! Why aren't you putting the blame on me?!
((俺のせいで負けたんだろうが
お前がいくら拾たて
We only lost the match because of me!
Any ball you could've saved would've been pointless because I couldn't make them count!
スパイクが決まんなきゃ
意味ないんだよ
Asahi!
((旭
(西谷)
((意味ないてなんですか
What do you mean, pointless?
((じゃあなんで最後
トス呼ばなかたんですか
Okay, then why didn't you call for the set at the end?
((打てる体勢でしたよね
You were in position.
((おいやめろよ西谷))
Lay off, Nishinoya!
((俺が旭にばか
ボル集めてたから疲れて
It's my fault for sending all the sets his way. He got overwor—
Even if you did set it for me, I couldn't make it count.
(東峰)((俺に上げたて
どうせ決めらんねぇよ))
((打てみなきゃ
分かんねぇだろうが
You don't know that until you hit the damned thing!
You never know! The next one might get through!
次は
決まるかもしれないじゃねぇか
((バキン
(菅原)((あ
Don't you dare give up on a ball I keep in play!
((俺が繋いだボルを
あんたが勝手に諦めんなよ
Noya!
(田中)((ノヤ
((俺はリベロだ
守備の要でチムの要だ
I'm a libero!
I'm pivotal to defense, and pivotal to the team!
((けど俺に点は稼げない))
But I can't earn us any points.
(西谷)((俺は攻撃ができない
I can't attack, but I don't care how many spikes don't get through.
でもどんなに
スパイクが決まんなくたて
I wouldn't blame you in the least.
責めるつもりなんか微塵もねぇ))
((だけど
勝手に諦めんのは許さねぇよ))
However, I don't forgive anyone who up and quits on me!
(田中)((あ旭さん
(菅原)((旭待てよ旭
Asahi!
Wait, Asahi!
((昨日なんで部活
来なかたんですか
Why didn't you come to practice yesterday?
新年度になたら
すぐインタハイなんですよ))
The interhigh happens soon after the start of the new school year.
((決まんないスパイク打たて
楽しくないからな))
It's no fun hitting spikes that count for nothing.
(東峰)≪何言てんだ
そんなこと少しも思てねぇ≫
What am I talking about? That's not how I think at all.
((お前だて拾ても
点に繋がんないなら虚しいだろ))
It's gotta be futile for you to retrieve balls that never count.
Stop it. Nishinoya doesn't think like that.
(東峰)≪やめろ西谷は
そんなふうに思うヤツじゃない≫
Suga feels responsible every time I get blocked—
(東峰)((スガも
俺が止められる度責任感じて
It doesn't matter what anyone else thinks!
((ほかのヤツがどう思うかなんて
関係ねぇよ
出してるのは
Hey! Who's doing all that shouting?!
廊下で騒ぐんじゃない
((旭さん
Quiet in the halls!
Asahi!
((おい))
(西谷)((うるせぇ
Hey!
Shut up!
50th Anniversary
((≪ガシャン
(教頭)((ひなんてことを
What have you done?
Uh, oh. Right in front of the Vice Principal.
(生徒)((割れちゃてる))
(生徒)((教頭の前で
(教頭)((あぁ
(西谷)((あんたはまたスパイク
決めたいて思わないのかよ
Don't you want to make a spike count again?!
(田中)ナイス日向
Nice, Hinata!
Thank you!
あざす
日向次サブ
Hinata, it's your turn to serve.
(東峰)思うよ
I do want to.
(東峰)何回ぶつかたとしても
もう一回打ちたいと思うよ
No matter how many times I run up against it,
I do want to hit it one more time.
(西谷)それならいいです
That's all that matters.
それが聞ければ十分です
That's all I needed to hear.
≪俺の仕事は
ただひたすら繋ぐこと≫
My only job is to keep the rally going.
(縁下)日向ナイサ
ん
Hinata, give us a good one!
(滝ノ上)ネトイン
うおとすまんカバ頼む
It's over the net!
Oops!
Sorry! Cover me!
ロン毛のにいちゃんラスト頼む
Long-haired guy! Seal the deal!
(西谷)
≪空はスパイカたちの領域で
The skies are the spikers' domain.
It's not a place where I can fight...
俺はそこで戦えないけど
止めんぞ
(月島)命令しないでくんない
We're stopping him!
Would you please not order me around?
We're playing for realsies, Asahi!
(田中)本気で行くす旭さん
(西谷)
≪繋げば繋いでさえいれば
...but so long as I keep the rally going...
(東峰)
((もう一回打ちたいと思うよ))
I do want to hit it one more time.
≪きとエスが決めてくれる≫
...our ace will definitely score.
≪重
That's heavy!
うお上がた
(内沢)ナイスフォロ
It's up!
Nice save!
(西谷)((ブロクフォロだな))
Blocked ball retrieval.
Specialized training to retrieve any blocked ball!
((ブロクされたボルを
拾いまくる特訓))
Noya!
ノヤさん
え
I'm going to keep that ball in play even if it rebounds off their wall of blockers.
(西谷)壁に跳ね返されたボルも
俺が繋いでみせるからだから
So please, call for a set just one more time...
だからもう一回
トスを呼んでくれエス
ace!
(嶋田)カバ
オライ
Cover it!
Got it!
≪どうする誰に上げる
What do I do? Who do I give it to?
The open left side is probably the most certain,
≪たぶんレフトからのオプンが
いちばん確実≫
but what if I give it to Asahi, and he gets blocked again?
≪でももう一回旭に上げて
また止められたら
菅原さん
Sugawara!
もう一回決まるまで
Send them his way until he scores!
ドＳだねぇ王様
ああ
You're such a sadist, King.
Huh?!
≪苦しいときや
レシブが乱れたとき
When the going is tough and when the receives are all over the place,
ラストボルを託されるのが
エス≫
the ace is the one you trust.
≪分かてる分かてるけど
I know that. I know that, but...
トスを待てない
旭にトスを上げて
I can't set for Asahi if he isn't expecting it and force him to take on a three blockers.
３枚ブロクと
勝負させるなんて
(東峰)≪スパイクが
A spiker can only move in for a spike after the set is made.
スパイクが打てるのは
トスが上がるから≫
(菅原)((もう一回
俺にトス上げさせてくれ旭))
Please let me set for you one more time, Asahi.
(東峰)≪トスが上がるのは
そこへ繋ぐレシブがあるから≫
The set exists because a receive kept the ball in play.
(西谷)((俺が繋いだボルを
あんたが勝手に諦めんなよ
Don't you dare give up on a ball I keep in play!
(東峰)≪そのスパイクを
打つのだて俺だけじゃない≫
I'm not alone when I move in for a spike.
(東峰)≪みんながそれぞれの
仕事をしていたのに俺は
Everyone else was doing their jobs, but I...
((一人で勝てないの当たり前です))
It's only natural that you can't win all by yourself.
That is why everyone calls you the ace.
((だからみんな
旭さんをエスて呼ぶんだ))
If there's a chance you might still like volleyball...
(澤村)((まだ
バレが好きかもしれないなら
So please, call for a set just one more time...
(西谷)((だからもう一回
トスを呼んでくれエス
ace!
オライ
(菅原)嶋田さん
Here!
Shimada!
Suga!
One more!
もう一本
≪ああエスが待てる
Right.
The ace is waiting.
トスを呼んでる≫
He's calling for the set.
≪ネトから少し離した
高めのトス
A high set, placed slightly in front of the net.
何本も何本も上げてきた
旭の得意なトス
Asahi's favorite set. The one I've given him so many times.
単純なこのトスでも
精一杯丁寧に≫
I make this, the most simple set, with as much care as I can.
君向こうのチムに
肩入れしてんの
Are you backing the other team?
We're gonna have to block him again.
悪いけどまた止めるよ
当然だ
Obviously. There's no point cutting corners.
手なんか抜いたら
なんの意味もねぇよ
(東峰)≪頼もしい背中の守り
He's always got my back.
俺のための
いちばん打ちやすいトス
He gives me the sets I find easiest to hit.
不足なんてない≫
I couldn't ask for more.
≪単純で当たり前のことを
いつの間にか忘れていた≫
Somewhere along the way, I'd forgotten the simplest, most natural thing.
≪俺は
独りで戦てるんじゃない
I'm...
not fighting alone!
≪打ち切てこそ
Going through with the hit is what it means...
≪エス
to be the ace!
Next Episode Preview
Tanaka, stop crying and block properly.
(月島)田中先輩泣いてないで
ちゃんとブロクしてくださいよ
You idiot! I'm not crying!
(田中)バカ野郎
泣いてなんかねぇ
This is—
Yeah, yeah. You're gonna say it's sweat, right?
これは
(月島)はいはい汗ですよね
It's my runny nose.
Episode Ten:
The Dream
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
(田中)鼻水だ
"The Dream."